Edwing Daniel García Martínez

Sr. Software Engineer / Full Stack with 12 Years of Experience Mexico City, MX | +52 56 1166 5081 | im@danielgarcia.me - dannegm@gmail.com

About me

I'm a self-taught developer with 12 years of experience in software development. I specialize in web solutions and am continuously growing towards software architecture. Always aiming to innovate, enhance user experience, and experiment with new technologies and trends.

Work Experience

Adelaide - Encora Inc. | Fullstack Architect | May 2022 - Current

• Created Adelaide's main product using ReactJS, Next, Docker, and Laravel. Maintained legacy applications and provided support for CI/CD processes and AWS management.

Etsy - Wizeline | Research & Development | November 2021 - April 2022

• Researched and developed new features based on user requests for adding innovation, utilizing Etsy's tools and technologies like PHP, Swift, Kotlin, and Java for web and mobile platforms.

Betterware - Wizeline | Teach Lead, Architect & Frontend Developer I March 2020 - October 2021

 Led the migration and architectural overhaul of the company's platform, implementing a cloud-based microservices and microfrontend ecosystem. Utilized GCP, C#, RabbitMQ, React, React Native, Jenkins, and Docker.

BrandNude - Independent | Frontend Lead, Frontend Architect | April 2020 - August 2020

 Led the rearchitecture and restructuring of an existing project, implementing best practices and a robust development plan to ensure its successful completion. Utilized tools such as React, TypeScript, Storybook, Figma, and GitLab CI.

Motive Drilling - Improving | Teach Lead, Architect & Frontend Developer / Feb 2018 - Feb 2020

Maintained legacy applications and developed new tools using modern technologies like VueJS.
Migrated specific Angular modules to VueJS.

Education

As a self-taught professional, my greatest academic achievements focus on sharing the knowledge I've gained over the past 12 years. Some examples include:

Wizeline Academy / Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

Speaker & Mentor | ReactJs Bootcamp

DW Training / Aug 2019 - Abr 2021

- Instructor | VueJS+Vuex Intermediate-Advanced Course
- Instructor | NodeJS Basic-Intermediate Course

Universidad de Guadalajara ft. TalentLand / Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

- Speaker | Components Architecture Exposition
- Speaker | Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality Exposition

Tech & Soft Skills

- Javascript / Typescript
- Nodels (Frontend/Backend)
- React / ReactNative / VuelS
- TDD / Jest / Cypress
- Go / Java / C# / PHP
- Git / Docker / CICD / AWS

- English C1
- Communication / Collaboration
- Responsibility / Confidence
- Teamwork / Leadership
- Agile / SCRUM
- Postgres / SQL / NoSQL